Emanuele Sansone

Email: e.sansone@hotmail.it Website: http://emsansone.github.io/ GitHub: https://github.com/emsansone

Summary

I'm a researcher with background in machine learning. Previously, I was working on statistical machine learning, focusing on understanding how to exploit unlabeled data in the context of semi-supervised, positive unlabeled and unsupervised learning (i.e. deep generative models and representation learning). My current research interests lie at the intersection between unsupervised learning and logic. Specifically, I'm interested in devising algorithms which can discover interpretable theories (in terms of logic programs) directly from noisy and ambiguous raw data. I have excellent organizational, communication and presentation skills developed over different teaching and supervising experiences at university as teaching assistant and in sports as ski coach and ski master instructor.

Education

2013-2018 | Ph.D.

ICT doctoral school, University of Trento, Italy

Thesis: "Towards Uncovering the True Use of Unlabeled Data in Machine Learning"

Advisor: Prof. Francesco G.B. De Natale.

2011-2012 M.Sc. in Telecommunications Engineering (magna cum laude)

University of Trento, Italy

Thesis: "Multimodal Photo Galleries Synchronization"

Advisor: Prof. Nicola Conci, Giulia Boato.

2008-2010 B.Sc. in Telecommunications Engineering

University of Trento, Italy

Thesis: "Master P-NET protocol implementation on PIC 32 architecture"

Advisor: Prof. Dario Petri, Eng. Michele Corrà.

Work and Research Experience

2020-to date | PostDoc Researcher

KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium

Advisor: Luc de Raedt.

2018-2020 Research Scientist

Huawei Technologies R&D, London, UK

Conducting research in the area of deep generative models and self-supervised learning. Supervising students on applied machine learning: Yinbai Li (Bachelor student in Mathematics at University of Cambridge), Xingyu

Jin (Master student in Computer Science at University of Edinburgh).

2015-2016 Research Internship

LAMDA group, Nanjing University, China

Advisor: Prof. Zhi-Hua Zhou.

Working on positive unlabeled learning.

Didactic Activities

2020	Teaching Assistant, Machine Learning and Inductive Inference (B-KUL-H02C1a-2021) M. Sc. in Computer Science, KU Leuven, Belgium
2016	Teaching Assistant, Computer Vision (Code 140266) M.Sc. in Telecommunications Engineering, University of Trento, Italy
2015	Teaching Assistant, Multimedia Networking (Code 140151) M.Sc. in Telecommunications Engineering, University of Trento, Italy

Professional Services

Program Committee Member: ECML/PKDD 2021.

Conference Reviewer: ICLR 2021-2022, NeurIPS 2021, AISTATS 2022.

Journal Reviewer: IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems, IEEE Transactions on Image Processing, Machine Learning (Springer).

Publications & Pre-prints

arXiv 2021	LSB: Local Self-Balancing MCMC in Discrete Spaces E. Sansone
arXiv 2021	Leveraging Hidden Structure in Self-Supervised Learning E. Sansone
ECAI 2020	Coulomb Autoencoders E. Sansone, H. T. Ali, J. Sun
PhD 2018	Towards Uncovering the True Use of Unlabeled Data in Machine Learning E. Sansone
PAMI 2018	Efficient Training for Positive Unlabeled Learning E. Sansone, F.G.B De Natale, Z.H. Zhou
arXiv 2017	Training Feedforward Neural Networks with Standard Logistic Activations is Feasible E. Sansone, F.G.B. De Natale
TMM 2017	Automatic Synchronization of Multi-User Photo Galleries E. Sansone, K. Apostolidis, N. Conci, G. Boato, V. Mezaris, F.G.B. De Natale
ECAI 2016	Classtering: Joint Classification and Clustering with Mixture of Factor Analysers E. Sansone, A. Passerini, F.G.B. De Natale

Invited Talks & Seminars

2019	Coulomb Autoencoders Invited Talk - Symposium on Deep Generative Models, British Computer Society, London, UK)
2017	Generative Adversarial Networks Seminar - Fondazione Bruno Kessler, Trento, Italy)

Awards

2021	Outstanding Reviewer Award ICLR 2021
2016	Academic Hardware Grant Award, NVIDIA Two Awards consisting of a NVIDIA Titan X GPU each
2012	Merit Award, University of Trento Trento, Italy

Learning Certificates

Online Courses (Coursera): Neural Networks for Machine Learning 2017, Algorithms Specialization 2020

Summer Schools: Machine Learning Summer School at University of Texas, Austin 2015, Full Stack Deep Learning Bootcamp at University of California, Berkeley 2018

Sport Professional Experience

2011-to date

Ski master instructor

Italy

This is the highest professional degree in alpine skiing (the total number of ski master instructors in Italy is around 200), which can be achieved by demonstrating excellent skiing capabilities as well as strong organizational, didactical and methodological skills used when coaching.

I hold several professional education and training courses for ski instructors and candidate ski instructors. The following is a list of people I prepared to become ski instructors: Alessandro Berlanda, Camilla Berlanda, Martina Kerschbaumer, Davide Raineri, Valentina Zampedri, Erman Baldessari, Federico Tonezzer, Martina Longobardi, Chiara Villotti, Stefano Gonzo, Francesca Cella, Samuel Piffer, Teo Valle, Martino Santoni, Emma Santoni, Thomas Corradino, Silvia Zeni, Marco Faccenda.

2007-2017

Ski coach

Italy

Coach of young athletes (6-20 years old) in several racing ski teams: Ski Team Sopramonte (2007/2008), Sci Club Padova (2008/2009), Sci Club Panarotta (2009-2011), Ski Team Paganella (2013/2014), Campiglio Ski Team (2016/2017).

2002-2007

Ski athlete

Italy

Participating in many international competitions. See a sample list of records.

Sport Certificates

2011 Ski Master Instructor

Milan, Italy
Certificate

Organization: FISI, CoScuMa

2011 Ski Coach (3° level)

Milan, Italy
Certificate

Organization: FISI, STF

2007 Ski Instructor

Trento, Italy
Certificate
Organization: PAT